http://www.pct.edu/about/penn-college-privacy

Skip to main content
Penn College Privacy
Home /
About /
We respect your privacy. Pennsylvania College of Technology is the sole owner of information collected on this website. Any and all information collected via the Penn College website will be kept strictly confidential and will not be sold, reused, rented, loaned, or otherwise disclosed. Exceptions exist only as mandated by law or required under a contractual relationship with a service provider as allowed by Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA).
We may provide your personal information to organizations that provide services to help us with our business activities. These organizations are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services. In addition, we require all outside organizations that we work with in any area of our organization, including marketing and data processing, to maintain the confidentiality of your information in accordance with this privacy statement and to comply with all applicable laws.
European Union General Data Protection Regulation
Special regulations apply to individuals that apply or are accepted to the College within the European Union.
Information Collection
Penn College collects information at several different points on our website including, but not limited to:
Student Information System (SIS)
You will use your Penn College username and password to log in to SIS. Information obtained via SIS includes personal information such as addresses and home information, grades, and account/billing information. You are encouraged to protect the privacy of your login credentials throughout your college career. Sharing network usernames and passwords is a violation of Penn College's IT Resources Acceptable Use Policy.
Registrar
The Registrar's Office requires a student's Social Security number for the purpose of verifying the student's identity with official educational records. If a Social Security number is not provided, the College cannot guarantee the authenticity of educational records. The College will not disclose Social Security numbers to anyone outside of the College without an individual's consent except as mandated by law.
Admissions
We request information from the user on our Information Request form, as well as our degree-seeking, non-degree-seeking, and returning student admissions applications. The data requested by the Information Request form is used for recruitment purposes. The data requested by the admissions application is used for enrollment and billing purposes. An applicant may also choose to remit their application fee online. This transaction is secured by VeriSign. The Admissions Office also requests advance registration for special events, such as Open House, Senior Visit Day, and Campus Tours; this information is used both for planning and recruitment purposes.
Financial Aid
We request information from the user on our Financial Aid Authorization form. While your Social Security number is not an admission requirement, it is required by the government in order for you to be eligible for aid.
Scholarships
We request information from the user on our Scholarship Application form. Our scholarship applications are hosted by NextGen Web Solutions. Applicants use their student ID number and a unique password (not the student's Penn College network password or SIS PIN) to log in. This information is contained on a secure server at NextGen.
The Penn College Fund Donor Form
The College contracts with Blackbaud, Inc., of Charleston, SC, USA, a leading provider of technology solutions and services for nonprofit organizations, to provide The Penn College Fund online giving form. The Blackbaud Gateway safely processes all transactions and the Blackbaud Vault encrypts sensitive information to ensure all transactions are secure. The College has elected to not require user registration with Blackbaud from our donors, further ensuring your privacy. Neither the College nor Blackbaud will disclose or share financial information without your consent, except for general statistical purposes and certain explicit circumstances in which disclosure may be required by law. Your financial information will not be distributed or sold to third-party organizations. Read the Blackbaud Privacy Policy for more information.
For those who wish to give to The Penn College Fund without submitting sensitive information online, we also provide a printable form that can be mailed to the Institutional Advancement Office.
Alumni Information Update
Alumni Relations offers an Information Update form to maintain current contact information and supply information for Class Notes published in Penn College Magazine. Alumni may elect to opt out of email from the Alumni Relations office.
We have also asked alumni, on occasion, to act as ambassadors for the College, to appear and give testimony for our publications and website, and to offer tours during College events such as Open Houses.
We do not share contact information with anyone outside the College without permission.
The College Store
The College contracts with Missouri Bookstore to provide online shopping cart technology for purchases. The user's email address will not be shared with anyone, and the user will receive no correspondence unless it relates directly to a question or order. Missouri Bookstore uses secure SSL technology to secure all transactions.
Workforce Development
We accept online registrations for noncredit classes taught through our Workforce Development office. The information is used solely for registration purposes. Also, because we accept credit card payment, this site is secured.
Wildcat Wishes
We accept online orders for "Wildcat Wishes" student gift packages. Information obtained is used for ordering and delivery purposes only. Neither party's name will be placed on a mailing list. Credit card orders are protected, since the site is secured.
Police
We request information from the user on our Student Vehicle Registration form, including vehicle license and credit card information. This transaction is secured.
Employee Directories
While we do not sell or give out email address information, that information is available on our website for the convenience of our students and employees. We do not publish a list of email addresses.
Student Directories
Student record information is confidential and private. In accordance with both federal law and College policy, the College does not publicly release student record information without prior written consent. The one exception to this is that the College will release directory-type information, such as name, address, phone number, date and place of birth, major, activity participation, date(s) of attendance, enrollment status, grade level, date of graduation, degrees/honors/awards, sports participation, and most recent educational institution attended. Any student may request that directory information not be released publicly by completing and signing an Authorization to Withhold Directory Information, available from the Registrar's Office.
Site Search
The College uses Google Custom Search for providing customized search results. Submitted queries are not stored by the College; rather they are shared with Google for processing. Use of the Google Custom Search on the College's website is governed by Google’s privacy policy.
Cookies
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive, and contains information about the user. Use of a cookie on the College's public website (www.pct.edu) is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. The cookie we use will stay on the user's hard drive. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site with no limitations. Cookies on our site are used solely for the purpose of tracking the progress of visitors to our site.
Log Files/IP Addresses
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses accessing the College's public website are not linked to personally identifiable information.
email Addresses requested on forms
We request your email address only to allow us to respond to your messages, or to forward a confirmation to you. We do not sell or give your email address to anyone for their personal use, and will not use it in any manner other than that specified on each form.
Links
This website contains links to other sites, and these links are designed to open all external websites in a new browser window. Pennsylvania College of Technology is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.
Notification of Change
The College will occasionally update this Statement. Those changes will be posted to this page so our constituents are always aware of what information is collected and how we use it. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information.
How to Report Privacy Violations
You may report violations of this statement with the form below.
Solve this simple math problem and enter the result. E.g. for 1+3, enter 4.
The future needs you
If you put more into today, could you get more out of tomorrow? If you create your future at Pennsylvania College of Technology, the answer is yes.
With open and rolling admission, applying is easy.
Apply today
Experience all that campus has to offer with visit options designed just for you.
Schedule visit
Get more information about the admission process.
Request information
